<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>https://example.org/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog #2: Economic Predictors</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/09/12/blog-2-economic-predictors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/09/12/blog-2-economic-predictors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;An incumbent president running for re-election reaps both benefits and barriers. For one, they are a candidate that the American people are familiar with and normalized to. That being said, the American people also have four years of work to analyze and interpret. The condition of the United States is put on the sitting Commander-in-Chief who is already in the position to lead the economy, culture, and social circumstances of their country. In the past decade, we&#39;ve seen Former President Barack Obama benefit in his re-election campaign against Mitt Romney, having been in a post-Hurricane Sandy relief era and reviving the economy after a significant bump during his mid-terms. On the other end, we saw Former President Donald Trump face the repercussions of controversial foreign relations, poor COVID-19 relief, and high unemployment in 2020.&#xA;&#xA;With this in mind, my second blog post will focus on different independent variables that can be used to predict the outcome of the 2024 election. Specifically, I will use economic variables to analyze their predictive abilities in elections between 1948 and 2020, in order to see the variable(s) best suited to predict the election in November. &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election Blog #1: Preliminary Prediction</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/09/09/election-blog-1-preliminary-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/09/09/election-blog-1-preliminary-prediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In politics and beyond, history can be an imperative indicator of what will happen in the future. Relative to other predictive models, elections can be difficult because the sample size is small and variant. Nonetheless, voting trends can and should be used to observe national trends.&#xA;American presidential elections have historically narrowed down to the Democratic and Republican candidates&amp;rsquo; respective vote share. The graph above highlights the competitive elections that have taken place between 1948 and 2020 in the United States. The competitive nature of these elections shows promise to our strong democratic systems. They also indicate the importance of using past elections to predict future ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
