<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>https://example.org/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Election Blog #6: Campaign Advertising</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/10/14/election-blog-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/10/14/election-blog-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With 3 weeks left until Election Day, American citizens are being bombarded by campaign advertisements on their TVs, social medias, and radio stations. In fact, recent reports showcase that a total half a billion dollars will be spent on advertisements by the two campaigns, with Vice President Kamala Harris dominating this spending amount with 63 percent of the total (The New York Times 2024). In the twentieth century, candidates have taken advantage of Americans&amp;rsquo; media usage to push their policy and personal agenda, which has coined the term &amp;ldquo;Air War,&amp;rdquo; following the 2008 Election where John McCain ramped up attacks against Barack Obama leading up to election day. While ads sometimes focus on the differences in policy, other times they hit on personal discrepancies. In 1988, for example, George HW Bush called out Micheal Dukakis in the &amp;ldquo;Tank Ride&amp;rdquo; ad for being anti-war previously, yet pro-war for the sake of winning the election. This as is often credited as being the defining reason Dukakis&amp;rsquo; campaign failed (Schulte 2008). The ads are especially focused on the key battle states in an effort to convince them in these crucial next 21 days before Election Day, which can be viewed in the distribution below, detailing the 2012 spending by state. (Digiday 2024).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election Blog #5: Demographics</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/10/06/election-blog-5-demographics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/10/06/election-blog-5-demographics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many stereotypes surrounding voter demographics and how they can predict presidential candidate support. Whether it be sexuality, occupation, or immigration status, Americans often mentally associate different identities with different parties. In an attempt to break these stereotypes, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen groups like &amp;ldquo;Gays for Trump,&amp;rdquo; which attempt to break oxymoronic identity alignments. We&amp;rsquo;ve also seen backlash to such beliefs among communities who believe that their specific needs won&amp;rsquo;t get represented properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election Blog #4: Incumbency</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/09/29/election-blog-4-incumbency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/09/29/election-blog-4-incumbency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 2024 Election holds a unique duel, being that it is between an incumbent president and a candidate from the incumbent administration. Many presidential models have special considerations when making election predictions based on incumbency adjustment. There are both advantages and disadvantages to incumbency. Generally, incumbents have an advantage when they have more media coverage (name recognition), campaign finance access, or &amp;ldquo;pork&amp;rdquo; (short term economic gains and credit-claiming). On the other hand, incumbents may be disadvantaged when there is a polarized electorate, recessions/disasters, or incumbency fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election Blog #3: Polling Predictions</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/09/22/election-blog-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/09/22/election-blog-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are numerous different resources that prospective voters can use to track an election. Almost every new outlet has their own poll, and major election tracking sites, like FiveThirtyEight, are publicly available for anyone to monitor. There&amp;rsquo;s great debate surrounding the purpose and benefit of polls. These polls are especially useful for campaigns to track shifts in their support between states and districts. It can also allow citizens to see how fellow Americans are reacting to current events across the country. However, polls have significant limitations. Sampling errors, biased methodologies, and low response rates can skew results. Additionally, they may influence voter behavior who can see one candidate drastically succeeding in their state, convincing them to stay home on election day. Unexpected events or late voter shifts can drastically alter outcomes, making predictions unreliable, but they are still a useful resource for researchers to predict election outcomes based on history and voter preferences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog #2: Economic Predictors</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/09/12/blog-2-economic-predictors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/09/12/blog-2-economic-predictors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An incumbent president running for re-election reaps both benefits and barriers. For one, they are a candidate that the American people are familiar with and normalized to. That being said, the American people also have four years of work to analyze and interpret. The condition of the United States is put on the sitting Commander-in-Chief who is already in the position to lead the economy, culture, and social circumstances of their country. In the past decade, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Former President Barack Obama benefit in his re-election campaign against Mitt Romney, having been in a post-Hurricane Sandy relief era and reviving the economy after a significant bump during his mid-terms. On the other end, we saw Former President Donald Trump face the repercussions of controversial foreign relations, poor COVID-19 relief, and high unemployment in 2020.&#xA;With this in mind, my second blog post will focus on different independent variables that can be used to predict the outcome of the 2024 election. Specifically, I will use economic variables to analyze their predictive abilities in elections between 1948 and 2020, in order to see the variable(s) best suited to predict the election in November.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election Blog #1: Preliminary Prediction</title>
      <link>https://example.org/note/2024/09/09/election-blog-1-preliminary-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/note/2024/09/09/election-blog-1-preliminary-prediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In politics and beyond, history can be an imperative indicator of what will happen in the future. Relative to other predictive models, elections can be difficult because the sample size is small and variant. Nonetheless, voting trends can and should be used to observe national trends.&#xA;American presidential elections have historically narrowed down to the Democratic and Republican candidates&amp;rsquo; respective vote share. The graph above highlights the competitive elections that have taken place between 1948 and 2020 in the United States. The competitive nature of these elections shows promise to our strong democratic systems. They also indicate the importance of using past elections to predict future ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
